Guide to the Grayson Louis Kirk Papers
Rare Book and Manuscript Library Columbia University Libraries
Grayson Louis Kirk Papers
1958-1984.
Kirk, Grayson L. (Grayson Louis), 1903-1997.
3 linear ft. (7 document boxes)
Columbia University Rare Book and Manuscript Library, Butler Library, New York, NY 10027.
MS#0716
4078452
Biographical Note
Professor of Government 1943-1948, Provost 1949-1950 and President 1953-1968, Columbia University.
Scope and Content
The collection containd correspondence, memoranda, drafts, committee meeting reports relevant to the operation of Columbia University, including the gymnasium, faculty members and real estate holdings on Morningside Heights and elsewhere. Also included are books from his library.
Arrangement
Collection is arranged into three series
Series I: Topical Office Files, 1958-1984
Series II: Correspondence, 1968
Series III: Books from Kirk's Library
Subjects
Columbia University--Administration.; Eisenhower, Mamie Doud, 1896-1979.; Brzezinski, Zbigniew, 1928-; Photoprints
Acquisition
10/--/86 M-86-10 Office of the Secretary Transfer
Transfer from Secretary of University, 1986.
- Series I: Topical Office Files, 1958-1984
  This series includes files relating to a number of campus projects and issues Kirk with which Kirk was involved. Most of the folders are topical, but there are alphabetical correspondence files that include correspondence not directly related to one of the topics with its own folder
  - A-Correspondence (Box 1)
  - Academy of Political Science (Box 1)
  - Alumni Federation (Box 1)
  - Altschul, Frank (Box 1)
  - American Association of University Professors (Box 1)
  - American Council on Education. (Box 1)
  - Arts, School of the (Box 1)
  - Association of American Universities (Box 1)
  - B-Correspondence, (2 Folders) (Box 1)
  - Bramish, Alleyn (Albany) (Box 1)
  - Buell, Temple (Box 1)
  - Bloor - Pulitzer Prizes (Box 2)
  - Bloor, William (Box 2)
  - Chamberlain, Lawrence H. (Box 2)
  - Charter Day (Box 2)
  - Cordier, A.W. (Box 2)
  - D-Correspondence (Box 2)
  - Delafield (Box 2)
  - E-Correspondence (Box 2)
  - Eisenhower, D.D. (Box 2)
  - F-Correspondence (Box 2)
  - G-Correspondence, (2 Folders) (Box 2)
  - Garrett, ProHenry E. (Box 2)
  - Gymnasium, 1958 (Box 2)
  - K-Correspondence (Box 2)
  - L-Correspondence (Box 2)
  - McGill, William J. (Box 2)
  - McGill Luncheon for April 4, 1972) (Box 2)
  - Pulitzer Prize Board (Box 2)
  - Pulitzer Prizes (Box 2)
  - Real Estate (Box 3)
  - Reid Hall, (2 Folders) (Box 3)
  - Teacher College (Box 3)
  - W-Correspondence (Box 3)
  - Wheeler, John W. (Box 3)
- Series II: Correspondence, 1968
  The correspondence series is primarily composed of letters received by Kirk on the occassion of his retirement from active duty at Colimbia and his being named President Emeritus of the University. Many of the letters include carbon copies of Kirk's replies.
  - Kirk Correspondence, 1968 (Box 7)
- Series III: Books from Kirk's Library
  - Books from Kirk's Library (Box 4-6)
    This series contains books from Kirk's library which have been inscribed and signed by Columbia authors including Jacques Barzun, Lloyd Motz and James T. Shotwell